# **AKINDAHUNSI, Samson Sunday**

Agbowo Residential Area, Beside Hosanna Hospital, U.I, Ibadan, Oyo, Nigeria . +234 810 086 8877 | akindahunsisamson25@gmail.com

#### PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Highly organized and efficient graduate of Mathematics with an unparalleled ability to learn fast, think critically, and adapt to new technologies. Possess strong work ethic and an ability to conduct research to resolve complex problems while also combining bilingual fluency in written and verbal English with excellent interpersonal skills to develop rapport with managers, clients and co-workers.

#### **KEY ATTRIBUTES**

- ✓ Basic Skills: able to perform complex mathematical calculations.
- ✓ Excellent numeracy and analytical thinking skills.
- ✓ Detail-focused.
- ✓ Commercial awareness.
- ✓ Computer proficiency (Microsoft Office, Microsoft Excel, PowerPoint and Creative Adobe Tools).
- ✓ Customer Orientation capable of establishing and maintaining long-term customer relationships, building trust and respect by consistently meeting and exceeding expectations.
- ✓ Capable of using effective communication skills to work with others in everyday situations.
- ✓ Quick learning abilities with aptitude for grasping new techniques.
- ✓ Possess a genuine enthusiasm and passion for calculations and problem-solving.
- ✓ Admirable ability to maintain high standards of discipline and produce high quality service.

# **EDUCATION**

#### **BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN MATHEMATICS | Second Class Honours**

2013 - 2018

FEDERAL UNIVERSITY OF AGRICULTURE, Abeokuta, Ogun State, Nigeria

Modules: Abstract and Linear Algebra, Mathematical Modelling and Methods, Functional and Complex Analysis

# **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

#### **EXECUTIVE ASSISTANT**

**MARCH 2020 - OCTOBER 2020** 

## CITYPOINT TREASURES LTD., Ikeja, Lagos, Nigeria

CityPoint Treasures Ltd is a fast-growing and go-getting organization with extensive experience focused on delivering integrated services in the area of Haulage and Logistics Management, Investment Financing, General Procurement and Supply, International Trade and Project Consultancy, and Oil and Gas Services needed for the 21st century.

#### **Duties and Responsibilities**

- ✓ Schedule appointments, and maintain and update supervisors' daily calendar.
- ✓ Coordinate travel arrangements, prepare itineraries, plan logistics, and submit expense reports.
- Screen all incoming phone calls, inquiries, visitors, and correspondence, and route accordingly.
- ✓ Maintain confidentiality of highly sensitive information.
- ✓ Manage complex office administrative work requiring the use of independent judgment and initiative.

# **Notable Accomplishment**

With my supervision as Executive Assistant, the company was able to procure the National Social Insurance Trust Fund – NSIFT Compliance certificate required by any contractors or supplier dealing with the Federal government of Nigeria.

#### YOBE SCHOLARS' ACADEMY, Yobe State, Nigeria (N.Y.S.C. Primary Place of Assignment)

Yobe Scholars' Academy is a globally recognized award-winning private secondary school which has over time produced bright minds excelling both academically and in character across the North-eastern region of Nigeria.

#### **Duties and Responsibilities**

- ✓ Created comprehensive lessons plans and various methods of teaching to ensure pupils were actively engaged in class.
- ✓ Meticulously recorded and organized students' attendance as well as their academic progress sheet to maintain up-to-date student files.
- ✓ Offered after-school tutoring to aid struggling students to improve their academic performance.
- Encouraged arithmetic critical thinking: planned and supervised purposeful assignments on basic mathematical methods and algorithms.

#### **Notable Accomplishment**

With my supervision as Mathematics Teacher,

Yobe Scholars' Academy was able to successfully organize and conduct mathematics quizzes to:

- √ keep students alert,
- ✓ enhance mathematical efficiency as well as productivity and
- ✓ Ultimately develop a passion for mathematics in students from the Northern part of Nigeria.

# SUPERVISORY PRESIDING OFFICER (SPO)

**FEBRUARY 2018 – MARCH 2018** 

GENERAL ELECTION, Yobe State, Nigeria

# INDEPENDENT NATIONAL ELECTORAL COMMISSION, NIGERIA (INEC)

Supervisory Presiding Officers are Federal public servants (serving corp members) recruited by the Independent National Electoral Commission (INEC) to instruct, supervise, and monitor all electoral activities carried out by Poll Clerks at the polling station so as to ensure a hitch-free, fair, and credible election process in a calm atmosphere; of which I was selected to supervise the 2018 INEC General Election at Godon-kuka village, Fika L.G.A, Yobe State.

#### **Duties and Responsibilities**

- ✓ Combined excellent communication and interpersonal skills in dealing with voters.
- ✓ Ensured safety of agents, sensitive materials, and voters at the polling station.
- ✓ Maintained effective time management by delegating tasks, prioritizing requests, and apportioning breaks to the electoral staff of my polling unit.

#### **Notable Accomplishment**

With my supervision as Supervisory Presiding Officer of Godon-kuka village, Fika L.G.A, Yobe State, electoral officials were able to carry-out proper cross-examination of non-statutory and statutory forms for voting and accreditations after the election processes.

### FRONT- END DEVELOPER (INTERNSHIP)

JANUARY 2016 - FEBRUARY 2017

JUSTWEB TECHNOLOGY, Lagos State, Nigeria.

JustWeb Technology is an award winning IT agency which specializes in website design, mobile and software development, and training tech-savvy individuals.

# **Duties and Responsibilities**

- ✓ Performed front-end web development for interactive web applicants to improve functionality and user experience using HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, JavaScript, mySOL
- Supported and collaborated with senior developers to test and optimize existing code architecture for long-lasting stock stimulation using AngularJS.

#### **Notable Accomplishment**

Worked with a team of six (6) front-end and back-end developers to develop a road traffic control web application, eKO Traffic.

# **CERTIFICATIONS AND AWARDS**

DISCHARGE CERTIFICATE  NATIONAL YOUTH SERVICE CORPS (NYSC)	2019
COMMENDATION CERTIFICATE OF RECOGNITION NCCF, Yobe, Nigeria	2019
HONORARY AWARD STATE MUSIC AWARD, NCCF, Yobe, Nigeria	2018
PROJECT MANAGEMENT PROFESSIONAL OUR GROWTH INTERNATIONAL, Nigeria	2019
HUMAN RESOURCES MANAGEMENT OUR GROWTH INTERNATIONAL, Nigeria	2019

# **EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES**

STATE MUSIC DIRECTOR NCCF, Damaturu, Yobe State, Nigeria	AUG 2018 – FEB 2019
CHOIR COORDINATOR RCCG MERCYLAND and AREA HQ, Ogun State, Nigeria	JAN 2017 – JAN 2018